### JOSEPH BRIMEYER

Phone: (206) 396-3998 | Email: <u>JBrimeyer@gmail.com</u> | Seattle, WA 98023 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joe-brimeyer/ | Portfolio: https://www.joebrimeyer.com/ |

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/josephbrimeyer">https://github.com/josephbrimeyer</a>

#### SUMMARY

A Full Stack Web Developer with a certificate from the University of Washington coding boot camp program. Professional experience in Operations Management, advanced degree in History, and a commitment to life-long learning. Critical thinking, passionate coder with a talent for leveraging technology to solve problems. Strength in building projects from concept to deployment by blending agile methodology with CI principles.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL, C#.

**Applications:** GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, SAP.

**Tools:** Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize.

#### **PROJECTS**

## DevConnect | GitHub: https://github.com/josephbrimeyer/DevConnect | Deployed: http://devconnexion.com/

- Summary: A Full-Stack application that allows for developers to connect with each other.
- Role: Front-End and Back-End development and integration, API calls, Configuration, Project Management.
- Tools: Material UI, Microsoft Azure, React, Node.js, Sequelize, Express, JavaScript, LinkedIn, Rapid API, GitHub.

## CineMentality | GitHub: https://github.com/josephbrimeyer/CineMentality | Deployed: https://young-reef-08407.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A site to search for triggers in movies for those with mental health issues.
- Role: Back-End development, Authentication, MVC Framework, Project Management.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, Bootstrap, Passport, Express, Sequelize, Heroku, GitHub.

# Band Tour Manager | GitHub: https://github.com/josephbrimeyer/band-tour-manager | Deployed: https://merkraith.github.io/Band-Tour-Manager/

- Summary: Site for locating upcoming concerts by band or artist.
- Role: Front-End development, API integration, Project Management.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, API, Material UI, GitHub.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Head Basketball Coach**

2017 - Present

CYO Youth Sports Seattle, WA

- Mentored athletes to improve their personal development and sportsmanship.
- Introduced games and drills which helped students to develop better skill levels.
- Encouraged everyone to cultivate a strong work ethic by demonstrating diligence, patience, and respect for others.

## Office Operations Supervisor Department of Commerce

07/2020 -11/2020

Seattle, WA

- Supported all field operations for group quarters during the 2020 census count.
- Drove strategies and activities to ensure all data was collected and processed.
- Supervised clerks and directed office workflow, ensuring smooth day-to-day operations and accurate completion of tasks.
- Attained security clearance through a federal government background check.

### Distribution Market Leader Dawn Food Products

10/2018 -05/2019

Renton, WA

- Operated two distribution centers, ensuring all orders were meticulously organized and distributed to customers on time.
- Facilitated the successful financial performance of the DC's with \$50 million in sales.
- Integrated the SAP ERP system with business operations as a specialist in SAP SCM, QM, BI, and IM.
- Reduced operational expenses by 15% through territory realignment and metrics tracking.

#### Operations Manager Dawn Food Products

02/2006 -10/2018

Renton, WA

- Drove sales growth of over \$40 million by streamlining processes and workflow.
- Coordinated training and operational support for 10 SAP implementations throughout the country by working with developers to ensure that the system was properly configured for optimal functionality.
- Utilized critical thinking and strong leadership skills to direct a team of supervisors, drivers, receivers, and selectors to achieve profitability.
- Achieved annual certification for our food safety program.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Certificate, Full Stack Web Development** – University of Washington Seattle, WA A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js, & ReactJS.

Master of Arts, History – DePaul University

Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Arts, History - Cornell College

Mt Vernon, IA